Sincro: wyxchari
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
博士，看!
Doctor, look!
照亮. 去外面拿个电筒.
A light. A torch outside.
你看见了吗?
Did you see it?
快点 Ben, 快!
Quickly Ben, quickly!
是什么?
What was it?
能回答我吗?
Can you answer me?
好像是某种脱离下来的肢体，某种爪子. 好吓人!
It was a sort of disembodied hand. A sort of claw. It was horrible!
不. 不, 什么也没有.
No. No, there's nothing.
你是对的 - 之前是有三个 Daleks.
You were right - there were three Daleks.
你知道那是什么?
Do you know what it was?
如果之前有三个，谁移动了?
If there were three, who moved it?
别问我. Lesterson?
Don't ask me. Lesterson?
但他还没有打开舱体啊.
But he hadn't opened the capsule.
他“说”他还没有打开．我们直接去找真相吧.
Now he said he hadn't opened it. Lets get our facts straight.
啊哈, 太棒了! 好想法，好想法.
Aha, excellent! Good thinking, good thinking.
什么, 那不是说你觉得他进去过?
What, does that mean you think he's been inside?
也许他一直在试验 Daleks? 啊
Perhaps he's been experimenting on the Daleks? Ah.
但是... 但他们是... 我是说他们已经死了. 肯定是!
But... but they're things I... I mean they're dead. They must be!
这盏灯是死的吧，现在看看!
This light is dead. Now the watch!
你是说这些东西只是需要能量?
Do you mean these things just need power?
嗯, Lesterson 太狂热了. 总督太在乎他自己的位置. 这让你想起什么了吗? 不知道. 没想过这个.
Now, Lesterson's fanatic. The Governor's jealous of his own position.
What does that suggest to you? Dunno. Hadn't thought about it.
这个基地所有事情都不太好，现在又多出来个 Dalek!
That all is not well with this colony. Add to that one Dalek!
噢, 天啊, you don't half make mountains, don't you? 就一个 Dalek?
Oh, blimey, you don't half make mountains, don't you? One Dalek?
是的! 只要一个就可以彻底荡平整个基地了.
Yes! All that is needed to wipe out this entire colony.
监察员? 监察员?
Examiner? Examiner?
Bragen, 你进屋之前从不敲门吗?
Bragen, don't you ever knock before you enter a room?
我很抱歉打扰了你. 我以为能在这里找到监察员，不是来找你的，Quinn.
I'm sorry if I disturbed you.
I was expecting to find the Examiner here - not you Quinn.
那, 他不在这里. 如果你想要到床底下看看，我就不管你了.
Well, he's not here. You'll probably want to start snooping
under the bed, so I'll leave you to it.
等一下.
One moment.
别想在我这里试你的运气, Bragen.
Don't try your luck with me, Bragen.
相反, 我正在尽力避免麻烦. 总督已经明确说过你不能跟监察员接触
On the contrary, I'm trying to avoid trouble. The Governor
gave express instructions that you were not to contact the Examiner
但我发现你在这里，相信你能提供一个合适的解释.
I find you here. I'm sure you can offer some suitable explanation.
我能. 但不是对你.
I can. But not to you.
在你走之前... 哦!
Before you go... Oh!
不要再试图挡我的道.
Don't ever try to block my way again.
保安!
Guard!
监察员不见了. 得马上找到他.
The Examiner is missing. He must be found immediately.
当然，真正的博士总是追着 Daleks 跑.
Of course, the real Doctor was always going on about the Daleks.
真正的博士?
Real Doctor?
真正的博士? 哦，你是说真正的博士.
Real Doctor? Oh, you mean the real Doctor.
是的，我看到过那个爪子，我可不想跟那个东西握手, let's put it that way.
Yeah, now I've seen that claw thing, well,
wouldn't want to shake hands with it, let's put it that way.
博士，你看, 如果他们有那么危险的话，你打算拿他们怎么办?
Doctor, look, if they're that dangerous, what are you going to do about it?
让我喘口气. Lesterson 会听吗? 哦, 哦. Lesterson listen.... 锻炼一下舌头. 试试 Lesterson listen...
Save my breath. Would Lesterson listen? Uh, uh. Lesterson listen..
Exercises the tongue. Try it! Lesterson listen...
看，他们认为你是监察员, 让他们把 Daleks 都销毁吧! 就这样，把你的权利都用上.
Look, they think you're the Examiner, order them to destroy the Daleks!
Well, chuck your weight about.
Lesterson listen, Lesterson listen, Lesterson listen...
你觉得你在干什么?
What do you think you're doing in here?
Listen, listen...
谁给你的权限?
Who gave you permission?
读读这个! 大声读!
Read this! Aloud!
授予所有权限.
Accord every access.
正确! 它并没说＂除了你的实验室＂，是吧? 除非使用小号字印的.
Exactly! It doesn't say 'except your laboratory' anywhere, does it?
Unless it's in micro-print.
我应该先问问的!
I should have been asked first!
当时你往舱体里看的时候，首先注意到的是什么?
What was the first thing you noticed when you looked inside that capsule?
嗯, 是... 是... 是 Daleks.
Well, th... th... the Daleks.
你被吓着了吧?
You were astounded?
是的．
Yes.
感到有点奇怪?
Amazed?
是的.
Yes.
你却没有看过他们一眼! 为什么? 因为你曾经到里面去过，看见过他们!
You didn't even give them a glance! Why?
Because you'd been in there and seen them!
第三个 Dalek 哪里去了?
Where is the third Dalek?
我不知道你在说什么!
I don't know what you're talking about!
你没经过允许就打开了舱体. 你发现了隔间里有三个 Daleks
You opened up the capsule without permission.
You found the inner contart... compartment containing three Daleks
你弄走了一个，藏了起来!
You took one of them away and you hid it!
藏起来? 简直... 胡说八道!
Hid it? What... what nonsense!
我能问问这是怎么回事吗?
May I ask what all this is about?
我们打开舱体里面的隔间时，Lesterson 早就进去过了.
We opened an inner compartment in the capsule,
and Lesterson had already been in there.
我不否认这个.
I don't deny that.
他偷了一个 Dalek!
And he's nicked a Dalek!
Dalek?
这是监察员给这个两个金属生物起的名字，我在舱体里面发现的那两个生物.
It's the name the Examiner has given to two metal creations
that I've discovered inside the capsule.
他们很危险，很邪恶.
And they're dangerous. Evil.
金属肿块而已! 非常不活跃.
Lumps of metal! Quite inactive.
那是你的想法，伙计．如果你看过...
That's what you think, mate. If you'd seen...
我想这是我作为一个科学家的指责，检查和调查这些东西．
I consider it's my duty as a scientist to...
to examine and investigate these objects.
现在请离开我的实验室，你们全部．别想染指我的实验!
Now please, all of you, keep out of my laboratory.
Keep your hands off my experiments!
那些＂金属肿块＂ - Daleks - 我期望他们坏掉，溶掉．我不关心什么方法，但要毁掉．
Those 'lumps of metal' - Daleks - I want them broken up, or melted down.
Up, or down, I don't care which, but destroyed!
我拒绝．
I refuse to allow it.
我是地球监察员 - 我要求这样.
I'm an Earth Examiner - I demand it.
这已经超过你的授权范围了.
You're exceeding your authority.
或许我们该问问总督的意见？我要马上见他!
Perhaps we should ask the Governor about that?
I wish to see him immediately!
那可能比较困难.
That might be difficult.
但不是不可能. Ben, Polly.
But not impossible. Ben, Polly.
他能够停掉这些实验不?
Could he stop the experiments?
我不知道. 这不关你们的事. 你去把 Janley 叫过来.
I don't know. It's none of your business.
You go and get Janley and then come back here.
我们没有... 没有时间浪费. 去吧，快，快!
We haven't... haven't got any time to waste.
Now go on man, quickly, quickly!
他可阻止不了我实验．一定有什么方法让你活过来 - 我要找到方法.
He won't stop me experimenting. There must be some way
to bring you back to life - and I'm going to find it.
当然你有权限访问任何地方.
And of course you do have the right of any access.
这就是为什么我有一块这样的牌子.
Which is why I have a badge which says so.
Lesterson 像一只母鸡一样看着他的创意.
Lesterson watches over his ideas like a mother hen.
如果地板上有个炸弹，还有５分钟就要爆炸了, 你在踹坏地板之前会不会先问我是否可以.. 啊, 水果!
If there was a bomb under this floor timed to go off in five minutes,
would you ask my permission before you ripped up the floorboards.. aha, fruit!
谢谢你.
Thank you.
监察员 - 这当然由你决定，但我建议你调查的时候慎重一下. 现在不是一个好的时间点.
Examiner - It's up to you of course, but I'd advise a little discretion
in your investigations. It's not a very good time, just now.
谢谢. 当前这些风风雨雨...
Thank you. With all these disturbances...
风风雨雨?
Disturbances?
是的, 一些小的破坏活动, 结党叛乱, 秘密报纸, 没什么太重要的. 但也让总督闲不下来
Yes, minor acts of sabotage, rebel cliques, secret newspapers,
nothing important you understand, but it keeps the Governor busy.
我毫不怀疑他会自己跟你说的, 我安排一下你们的会见．
I have no doubt he'll tell you about it himself when I arrange your meeting with him.
打算在什么时候?
When will that be?
啊, 他先要对基地全面巡视一下... 我看看他去之前能不能见你一下.
Ah, he's going on a tour of the perimeter of the colony.
I'll... I'll find out if he can see you before he goes.
谢谢.
Thank you.
看, 这是像这样的小事才让人难以相信你就是博士.
You know, it's little things like this
that make it difficult to believe that you're the Doctor.
啊.
Ahh.
另外一个，我是说. 真的那个. 喔, Nuts(呸/坚果)，你知道我什么意思.
The other one, I mean. The proper one.
Oh nuts, you know what I mean.
坚果(Nuts)? 是的,当然, 我们有了. 要饼干吗?
Nuts? Yes, certainly, here we are. Crackers?
你，我的古瓷器(china), 是个赝品!
You, my old china, are an out and out phoney!
中国(China), 是的, 我相信我曾经去过那里，碰到了马可波罗!
China, yes, I went there once I believe. Met Marco Polo!
不是，不是中国(China). 是瓷器(china)! 瓷器和盘子，朋友.
No, not China. China! China and plate, mate, friend.
是的，马可波罗是朋友? 我相信他是.
Yes, Marco Polo a friend? I believe he was.
别听他的，博士. 我知道你是谁.
Don't listen to him, Doctor. I know who you are.
嘘!
Shh!
啊, 这是个...
Ah, it's a...
诺, 诺, 几个小虫子. 小麦克风.
Well, well, a touch of the bugs. Microphones.
有人在偷听我们说话!
Someone's been listening to what we were saying!
是的, 这就是为什么你在满口说些乱七八糟的话!
Yes, so that's why you were messing about and talking nonsense!
我从不胡说!
I never talk nonsense!
嗯, 嗯, 嗯.
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
嗯~, 基本没有.
Well, hardly never.
他们相信我们还呆在屋子里，是吧?
Well, they certainly believe in making us at home, don't they?
一开始, 我就想可能不止一个.
At first, I thought there might be more than one.
我打赌是那个老Charlie Bragen 干得!
Here, I bet old Charlie Bragen did it!
是叫 Charlie 吗?
Charlie?
但是 Fred 这个名字不太适合他啊，是吧?
Well Fred wouldn't suit him would it?
如果他没做过，你觉得那是他自己的想法吗? 我是说 - 他可能是收到了命令.
If he did do it, do you think it was his own idea? I mean
- he could have been under orders.
你说可能来自总督? 啊, 我不知道. 你怎么想，博士?
You mean from the Governor? Ah, I don't know. What do you think, Doctor?
哦，是的. 当然. 我们... 我们先来看一下这个纽扣.
Oh, yes. Yes of course. Let's... let's consider this button for a moment.
这是我们手上关于监察员被害的唯一线索，那个真监察员.
It's the only clue we've got to the murderer of the Examiner.
The real Examiner.
唔. 谁要求他来这里的?
Hmm. And who asked for him to come?
Lesterson对于那个舱体的疯狂举动. 他不想让任何人打听.
Hmm. Well, Lesterson's crackers about that capsule.
He wouldn't want anyone nosing about.
Bragen 说总督那边一直麻烦缠身.
Bragen said the Governor's been having trouble.
好，先排除他. 总督都是一样的，他不会请求援助. 如果他发这样的信息，会让他看起来不能正确自己处理.
Naw, rule him out. Governors are all the same, he wouldn't ask for help.
If he sent the word it would look as if he couldn't do the job properly.
是的
Yes.
我建议先回到 TARDIS, 我有点受够了.
Oh, well, I vote we go back to the TARDIS, I've had enough of this dump.
是吗? Daleks 怎么办?
Have you? What about the Daleks?
他们是死的.
Well, they're dead.
我们在舱体里面看到的那个东西是怎么一回事 - 那可是活的.
Well, what about that thing we saw in the capsule - that was alive all right.
没法解释那个.
Well, can't explain that.
我能. 而且那就是为什么我们还不能走!
I can. And that's why we have to stay!
他们很丑陋的畜生是吧? 嘿, 他到底瞎倒腾这些干什么呢? 别管这个了, 要我说.
Ugly-looking brutes aren't they? Hey, what's he want to
muck about with them for? Leave well alone, that's what I say.
你就适合做个助手．别理这个? 如果这个星球上都是你这样的人, 我们不会有任何进展.
You're a fine one to be a research assistant. Leave well alone?
There'll be no progress on this planet with people like you around.
我们现在就要干这个, 否则你们这些家伙就会把事情搅乱.
We're doing all right as we are.
Or we were until your lot came along stirring things up.
你们跑不掉, 你知道的. 总督对于你们叛乱的事情全知道, 当他准备好之后会碾碎你们.
You won't get away with it, you know. The Governor knows all about you rebels.
He'll smash the lot of you when he's ready.
总督?
Governor?
对, 总督!
Yeah, the Governor!
他不可能碾碎...
He couldn't smash...
能不能安静一下! 你们俩以为自己是谁? 这是间科学实验室，请别把政治带进来.
Will you be quiet! Where do you both think you are?
This is a scientific laboratory. Kindly keep your politics out of it.
快点, Resno. 伙计, 动起来. 我们没有那么多时间.
Come on, Resno. Man, get on with it. We haven't got all day.
我们得在总督阻止我们之前搞定这个.
We've got to get this working before the Examiner stops us.
他有点害怕这些东西.. 这些 Daleks?
He's got some phobia about these.. these Daleks?
我知道他们的悲剧 - 毁灭. 但还有更恐怖的事情 - 我记不太清楚了.
I know the misery they cause - the destruction.
But there's something else more terrible - something I can only half remember.
博士, 到底是什么?
Doctor, what was it?
总督在哪儿? 他说了什么?
Well? Where is the Governor? What did he say?
他传达了歉意, 监察员．他今晚不能见你, 但期望明早第一个见你.
He sends his apologies Examiner. He can't see you tonight,
but he hopes to see you first thing in the morning.
哦, 但也许不用等那么久, Charl ... 哦, Bragen.
Well, it might not wait that long, Char... ah, Bragen.
还真早不了.
It will have to.
抱歉.
Excuse me.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
当然是去见总督.
To see the Governor, of course.
恐怕不可能．一旦他的门关上了, 没有人, 即便是你监察员, 也不允许进入他的房间!
I'm afraid that's not possible. Once his door is closed,
no-one, not even you, Examiner, is allowed into his room!
好吧.
Very well.
谢谢. 那就明早吧.
Thank you. Until the morning then.
这里发生了什么?
What happens now?
我应该联系地球. 那个叫 Hensell 的总督肯定听他们的 - 我得让地球支持我.
I shall radio Earth. Governor or not, Hensell will have to
listen to them - I'll get Earth to back me.
太搞笑了. I could have sworn. 你们呆在这里, 我很快回来.
That's funny. I could have sworn. You stay here, I shan't be long.
开始连接.
Connecting now.
所有连接正常.
All connections responding.
完全没反应?
Nothing at all?
没.
No.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
这里完全没问题.
There's nothing wrong here.
我们来看看.
Well, let's see.
真的. 我连表盘都不会读啊.
Really. If you can't trust me to read a dial.
安静. 好了 - 我们再试试. 这次我们调高到 3.24. 听到了吗 Janley?
Be quiet. All right - we'll try again.
This time we'll take it up to 3.24. Got that Janley?
3.24.
开始动了!
It's moving!
现在记下来, Janley. 一号附着物吸盘有反应. 二号附着物没动.
Now, note this, Janley. Number one attachment with sucker stick
responding. Number two attachment not moving.
三号附着物镜头有反应. 看看这些读数, Resno.
Number three attachment with lens responding. Watch these meters, Resno.
还有反应.
Still responding.
现在, 有理由假定这个有吸盘的棍子有着手一样的功能.
Now, it's reasonable to assume that this the sucker stick
acts like some kind of a hand.
没事 - 别大惊小怪. 我们只给了临时的能量.
It's all right - don't be alarmed. We've only introduced temporary power.
我们得打开它才能彻底搞明白它是怎么工作的.
We shall have to be able to open it up
before we could find how it works permanently.
这东西有一点吓人.
It's a bit frightening.
是的. 现在我没法想出这个短臂是干什么的.
Yes. Now, I cannot think what this short stubby arm is for.
这些镜头会是眼睛吗?
Could the lens attachment be an eye?
是的, 是的. 很有可能是． 啊, 这个叫做Dalek的东西... 肯定有某种directing influence.
Yes, yes, yes, yes. Now it's quite possible that this, ah, Dalek...
Now there must be some kind of directing influence.
这里甚至可能有一个简化的大脑. 正电子的, 我不会奇怪的. 要是我们能打开它就好了!
There may even be a simplified brain. Positronic,
I shouldn't wonder. If only we could open it up!
现在怎么办?
Now what?
所有都可以工作了.
Everything functioning here.
是的, 也许某个地方有能量泄露. 我们再试试.
Yes. Well, perhaps the power is leaking away somewhere.
We'll... we'll try again.
看它的眼睛!
Look at the eye-stick!
它在看我们!
It's watching us!
荒谬.
Don't be absurd.
真的. 我看见了!
It was. I saw it!
你不能说＂在看我们＂. 你这样会让我们觉得... 这东西好像有智力似的. 继续干活去吧!
You can't use the phrase 'watching us'. You'll have us believing that
th... the thing has intelligence next. Now, get on with your work, man!
我就知道你在这里.
I know you're there.
监察员, 谢天谢地, 是你啊. 你一到这里我就想来跟你谈谈.
Examiner, thank goodness, it's you.
I've been trying to talk to you ever since you got here.
这里发生了什么? 又是你.
What's happening here? You again.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我发现操作员没知觉了.
I found the operator unconscious.
我也发现了! 我正看着他, 就听见有谁在走动了. 肯定是你.
So did I! I was just looking at him, when I heard someone move.
It must have been you.
那些是...?
And those?
我刚捡起来的. 这都是怎么了?
I picked them up. What is all this?
这些线缆被剪断了.
The cables have been cut.
啊?
What?
这很严重. 不仅仅是内部通讯出了问题了，我们跟地球的联系也被切断了.
This is serious. It's not just our own communications.
We're cut off from Earth as well.
想干这个的只能是那些叛乱分子.
The only people who'd want to do that are the rebels.
你的那些四肢发达的小伙子要是有点脑子的话, 就能防止这些事情发生了.
Those muscle boys of yours had any brains,
they'd stop things like this.
Bragen, 我刚着陆就被攻击了. 这是我当时采集到的一个证物.
Bragen, I was attacked just after I landed.
This is a small souvenir I collected.
这个纽扣是你的吧?
This button belongs to you, doesn't it?
哦，是的.
Well, yes.
你说这个东西是你捡到的? 我觉得破坏通讯的也是你...
And you say you picked these up?
I suggest that you were sabotaging the communications...
那是瞎说!
That's a lie!
...还攻击了其中一个工程师. 有这些证据，我得让总督过一会儿再走.
...having first attacked one of the engineers.
I'd detain the Governor on evidence like that.
我期望你没打算让我过一会儿再走, Bragen.
I hope you're not thinking of detaining me, Bragen.
我没得选. 发生了这样的事, 我不可能再让你乱跑, 是吧? 过来，保安.
I've no option. I could hardly let you run around loose
after this, could I? All right guards.
我警告你, Bragen!
I warn you, Bragen!
好吧 - 这轮你赢了. 我们看看到了总督面前怎么说.
All right - you win this round, Bragen.
We'll see what it looks like in front of the Governor.
总督会安排一个质询的. 我能问问你在这里干什么吗?
The Governor will want an enquiry.
May I ask what you were doing here?
好. 我已经将能量导向别处了. 这次调高到 4.68. 呃... Resno, 你得在摄像机和表盘两边跑了.
Right. I've redirected power. This time working up to 4.68.
Eh... now Resno, you will have to dodge between the camera and your meters.
就绪.
Ready.
建立连接.
Connecting, now.
所有连接正常.
All connections responding.
很好.
Excellent.
行了!
It's working!
很好. 录下来, 现在就录, Resno. 对了, 记一下数据, Janley.
Excellent. Film it, film it now, Resno.
And, note the readings, Janley.
看来它对你有兴趣, Resno.
It seems to be interested in you, Resno.
你是怎么回事?
What's the matter with you man?
我告诉你它是有智能的. 他在看着我, Lesterson. 在打量我! 我能感觉到!
I tell you it's intelligent. It's watching me,
Lesterson. Weighing me up! I can sense it!
别傻了.
Don't be a fool.
我不喜欢这样, 我跟你说．我不知道这些东西能做出什么事情来．
I don't like it I tell you. I don't know what these things can do.
不, 我们永远不可能知道, 除非我们把它的每一个反应都拍下来. 继续你的工作, 伙计!
No, and we never shall know, shall we, unless we take film
of every reaction. Now get on with your work, man!
Resno!
没事．他没死.
It's all right. He isn't dead.
发生了什么?
What happened?
被冲击波震晕了.
Knocked out by the shock waves.
我们必须带他去医院, 我去叫人来帮忙.
We must get him to the hospital. I'll go and get help.
我们要帮 Quinn 作证
But we've got to defend Quinn.
是的,  我知道． 他是无辜的,  至少在证明他有罪之前．但他有罪.
Yeah, I know. He's innocent until he's proved guilty. But he is guilty.
他是副总督!
He's the Deputy Governor!
那又怎样? 我那会儿有个小头目被撸下来, 就只因为没交公交车费! 而且他这还是有动机的, 别忘了动机.
So what? I had a headmaster once who got nicked for not paying
his bus fare! And then there's the motive, don't forget the motive.
比如说是什么?
Like what for instance?
首先, 他是副总督, 对吧? 也许他想当总督.
Well, he's the Deputy Governor, right? Maybe he wants to be Governor.
哦, 这太荒谬了!
Oh, that's ridiculous!
那, 外衣纽扣总不荒谬吧! 而且他在通讯室里面被抓住时手里正拿着一把钳子
Well, the jacket button wasn't! And he was caught red-handed
in the Communications Room with a pair of pliers,
别跟我说他是拿那东西来剪眉毛的.
and don't tell me he was plucking his eye-brows either.
有些人你知道他们是没有问题的，你看见他们的样子就知道.
Look, there are some people you know are all right.
You just know by looking at them.
早上好. 质询马上要开始. 我被派来带你们过去.
Good morning. The enquiry is about to begin.
I've been sent to escort you.
你好 Janley.
Hello Janley.
到时间了吗?
Is it time?
是的, 我觉得到了. 我感到很兴奋.
Yes. Yes, I think so. I feel quite excited.
当然是. 这是个了不起的成就.
So you should. It's a wonderful achievement.
是的是的. 但最棒的是, Janley, 我们不知道这个实验的范围. 谁知道我们能走多远.
Yes, yes. But the wonderful thing, Janley, is that we don't know the full scope of this experiment. Who knows where we may go from here.
谁知道这 Dalek 可能做什么?
Who know what this Dalek may do?
它应该是无害的吧?
It's harmless now?
是的, 是的. I... 我已经去除了... 哦, Resno, 你今天见到 Resno 了吗?
Yes, yes, yes. I... I've removed... Oh, Resno, have you been to see him today?
见过.
Yes, yes.
怎样?
And?
他... 他在医院治疗呢. 他很快就没事了.
He... he's had medical attention. He's going to be all right.
哦, 那就好.
Oh, good.
最好没人发现这起事故，否则可能会让监察员找到他们想要的借口，他就能停掉这个项目.
No one must find out about this accident. It might give the Examiner
just the excuse they want, and he could stop the whole project.
嗯, 是是是, 你说的对.
Well, yes. Yes, yes, yes, you're right.
准备好了?
Well. Ready?
好了! 我们开始，让他们大吃一惊.
Yes! Let's go and surprise them.
我很抱歉没能早点见你，监察员。请坐。
I am sorry I couldn't see you earlier, Examiner. Please sit down.
Quinn, 我跟你一样不喜欢这个. 你都做什么了?
Well, Quinn, I don't like this anymore than you do.
What have you been up to?
什么也没有做.
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
那， Bragen 的报告是怎么回事? 这些是事实证据, Quinn. 现在，你还有什么要说的?
Well, what about Bragen's report then? These are facts, Quinn.
Now, what have you got to say about it?
那个工程师说是我打了他?
Does the engineer say I hit him?
他是被人从后面袭击的，他能怎么说?
How could he if he was hit from behind?
那就只有间接证据了.
Then its only circumstantial evidence.
监察员也在水银沼泽被人袭击了。这里有一颗你衣服上的纽扣，是在监察员手里找到的.
The Examiner was also attacked in the mercury swamp.
We have a button from your jacket, found in the Examiner's hand.
这个我没法解释.
I can't explain that.
我肯定你没法!
I'm sure you can't!
监察员.
Examiner.
你好像有两个大脑.
You seem to be in two minds.
对, 还有两个身体.
Yeah, and two bodies.
你向 Bragen 提及了 Lesterson 发现的那些机器... 你管他们叫什么来着?
You mentioned to Bragen that these machines of Lesterson's...
What do you call them?
他们本来的名字 - Daleks
I call them what they are - Daleks.
啊, 是是是, Daleks. 你说他们可能有动机破坏我们的通讯设施.
Ah, yes, yes, yes, Daleks. You say they could be a motive
for destroying our communications.
我说过.
I do.
Lesterson, 这是一场特别的质询. 请你...
Lesterson, this is a special enquiry. Now please.
等不急了. 你不会失望的!
This won't wait. You won't be disappointed!
你听到我说什么了 Lesterson!
You heard what I said Lesterson!
总督，我已经完成了一项实验，可给基地带来革命. 听我多说两句.
Governor, I've just completed a... an experiment
which could revolutionise the whole colony. Bear with me.
Lesterson, 你完成什么了？你完成什么了?
Lesterson, what have you done? What have you done?
我给你演示一下. Janley, 开始!
I'll show you. Janley, now!
它认出了博士. 它认得他.
It recognised the Doctor. It recognised him.
你怎么啦，博士? 有什么不舒服吗?
What's the matter, Doctor? Are you all right?
蠢人. 愚蠢之极.
The fools. The stupid fools.
你害怕啦! 它能干什么?
You're scared! What can it do?
目前还没有.
Nothing yet.
它知道你是谁! 虽然听起来很疯狂，但是真的.
It knew who you were! It sounds crazy, but it did.
知道我过去是谁.
Knew who I was.
Dalek 知道你现在是谁.
The Dalek knows who you are.
这个生物叫做, 按我的理解, 叫做 Dalek. 现在看看. FIXME
This creation is called, I understand, a Dalek. Now, look at it.
我只不过给了一点电力, 但它能够储存它．FIXME
I have merely given it electrical power.
But it is capable of storing it.
它还能对命令做出响应. 转一圈. 移动那个椅子.FIXME
Moreover, it responds to orders. Turn around. Move that chair.
停. 看见了吧. 想想这能给我们的挖矿, 流水线, 打包工作带来什么.FIXME
Stop. You see? Well, just think what this could do for our...
our mining program, our processing, packaging.
无数的劳工啊, 总督. 它甚至可以终结这个基地的所有问题.
Dozens of labour jobs, Governor.
It may even supply the end to all this Colony's problems.
是的, 它可以终结这个基地的所有问题, 因为它可以终结这个基地!
Yes, it will end the colony's problems, because it will end the colony!
我-是-你的-仆人.
I am your servant.
它... 它说话了! Janley, 你听到了吗? 它真的会说话!
It... it spoke! Janley, did you hear it? It can actually talk!
它能做很多事情, Lesterson. 但它干得最有效率的事情是终结人的生命.
It can do many things, Lesterson. But the thing it does
most efficiently is exterminate human beings.
它毁灭人类, 毫不留情, 毫无内疚. 它毁灭人类. 绝对地. 完全地. 毁灭人类.
It destroys them, without mercy, without conscience.
It destroys them. Utterly. Completely. It destroys them.